I've calculated that a fan can still
shell out a ton of money beyond what
they're paying FIFA.
Flight prices alone can easily dwarf the
cost of a ticket. And if you bought your
flight after the start of the Iran war,
it's likely higher than expected due to
rising fuel prices.
Then, there's the cost of your
accommodation and transportation to the
stadiums.
I calculated that if an Argentina fan
was [music] to fly from Buenos Aires to
Dallas with a layover in Atlanta to
attend the group stage game against
[music] Jordan, they'd spend about
$3,361,
which includes the tickets, the flight,
and an average three-star downtown
hotel. I'm a Scotland fan, so I also
looked up how much it would be [music]
to fly from Edinburgh to Boston to see
the team's first game against Haiti.
The breakdown is similar. The average
group stage game tickets cost a couple
of hundred dollars less, but hotels in
Boston cost more, driving up the total.
And while we're talking about Boston,
take a look at this extra bit at the
end. That represents transportation
costs. While FIFA is expected to
generate billions [music] of dollars
from the tournament, local governments
and transit operators, not FIFA, are
largely responsible for covering the
additional costs of handling the massive
influx of fans trying to get to and from
[music] the stadiums.
In Boston, a round trip train ticket
from downtown to Gillette Stadium, about
20 miles away, usually costs about $20.
But during the World Cup, the city is
charging $80. Similarly, New Jersey
Transit usually charges $12.90
for a round trip fare between Penn
Station and the MetLife Stadium. On the
day of a match, fans will have to cough
up $98 for the same trip.
In Florida, the Brightline train is also
charging a high markup.